fool.sg 2018-01-08

# Privacy Policy | The Motley Fool Singapore

The Motley Fool Singapore Pte. Ltd. (“The Motley Fool” or the “Fool”) is committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.   This Privacy Policy describes how we may collect, use and disclose the personal data of our website visitors, readers and members.

**If you have any queries or concerns regarding these practices, you should contact The Motley Fool:**

**The Information We Collect**

  * **Registration:** In order to read most of our articles, you must register with the Fool and provide us with your email address. We also capture your IP address.

  * **Signing Up for Content Delivered via Email:** When you sign up for a report or other content delivered by email, we will ask for your email address. We may also ask for your name as well as capture your IP address.

  * **Subscribing to a Premium Service:** When subscribing to one of our premium services, we need to know the sort of information typically used for credit card transactions, such as your name, address, telephone number, and credit card number and expiration date. We encrypt all of this information using Secure Socket Layers (SSL) technology.

  * **Other Services:** We may also ask for additional information when providing special or personalised services. If you do not want to give us the information requested, you certainly do not have to, but you will not be able to take advantage of such offerings. For example, if we launch a text alert feature, we would not be able to send you any alerts unless you provide us with your mobile number. On occasion, we may also ask you for other personal information in connection with surveys, sweepstakes or other promotional offers running on our site or a premium service but again, your participation in these features are purely voluntary.

**Where your Personal Data is Collected, Processed and Stored**

The information outlined above is collected through The Motley Fool, which is incorporated in Singapore and hence subject to the requirements of the Personal Data Protection Act 2012.  This information is then processed and stored in the United States, which we believe is a jurisdiction with a comparable level of personal data protection to Singapore.   As a result of this, your information may also be subject to US law and jurisdiction.   The Motley Fool takes steps to ensure that your personal data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and applicable law.

**Our Use of this Information**

  * **Member/Customer Services:** If you have a subscription or free membership with us, we will use the data you have provided to maintain your account and provide you with the services you have subscribed to (including physical delivery of any product you may have purchased or signed up for). We will also use your data to perform other customer service functions such as responding to your enquiries.

  * **More Customise Services:** The Motley Fool collects personal information to provide you with the best and most personalised web experience possible. In short, by knowing a little about you, The Motley Fool can deliver more relevant content and provide you with a more efficient, customise and seamless experience when using our services.

  * **Internal Research:** Cookies and other information we automatically track are used to help us better understand how our audience uses our site and our services as well as for internal research on their interests.  Each browser accessing The Motley Fool is given a unique cookie which is then used to determine usage patterns.

  * **To Contact You:** We may subsequently email you about our various products and services, or other products and services we feel may interest you. If you’d rather not receive these subsequent communications, [unsubscribe here](http://www.fool.sg/unsubscribe).

**Our Use of IP Addresses and Cookies**

**IP Addresses:** Your web browser or email application automatically provides your IP address to other computers with which you communicate over the internet, so that they know where to send you information.  We receive an IP address each time you view one of our web pages, because the browser automatically reports it to us. We also may store the IP address when you register with The Motley Fool.

We may use IP addresses for various purposes, including:

  * Diagnosing service or technology problems.
  * Assessing and maintaining system security.
  * Displaying the most appropriate content.
  * Studying how people use our site and how we can improve it.
  * Reporting to potential and existing business partners about aggregate, but not individual information derived from IP addresses.

**Cookies:**   If your browser is set up to accept them, we also use a feature known as a cookie. Cookies contain bits of information that web sites transfer to your computer’s hard drive for record keeping purposes. Cookies can make the web more useful by storing information about your preferences on a particular site such as ours.

At The Motley Fool cookies are used in the following ways:

  * To automatically access your previously account information;
  * To interact with other members of the Fool community either by article comments or in our forums; and
  * Access any premium content you have subscribed to.

You have the option of not accepting the cookies we set.  However, if you reject our cookies you will not be able to take advantage of most of the features on our site including the ones mentioned above.

Google Analytics:  We have implemented the Google Analytics Advertising Features, a web analysis service by Google, Inc. Google Analytics sets cookies so it can analyse how our users use our site. This service provides us with non-personally identifiable information such as browser type and aggregated demographic data.  If you would like more information about Google Analytics and how to opt-out, please visit [Google Analytics opt-out program](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) and its [privacy practices](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245).

**Information Sharing and Disclosure**

With the few exceptions that we explain below, The Motley Fool does not give, rent, lend, or sell individual information to any third party.  We may, however, provide aggregate information to current and potential business partners.  For example, we might tell advertisers that there are 120,000 Registered Fools in Metropolis, but we will not tell them that the user called ‘Superman’ is one of them, and we definitely will not disclose that his email address is [ckent@dailyplanet.com](mailto:ckent@dailyplanet.com).

We will disclose personal information only in the following circumstances:

  * **Fool Community:** In our forums (and anywhere else on our site), you are publicly identified by your user or screen name. If you choose your full name as your username, you have voluntarily disclosed that information to the Fool community. Similarly, any information you provide in your public profile is for public consumption.
  * **Parent Company:** Since our parent company, The Motley Fool, LLC (“Fool US”), handles the distribution of some of our emails for us, we provide our members’ email addresses to Fool US for the sole purpose of delivering these publications.
  * **Third Party Providers:** We may employ the services of third party providers to aid us in certain aspects of our operations (such as the distribution of our email products or conducting a survey for us). Depending on the services performed, some of these providers may be provided with your personal data. These contractors would be subject to confidentiality agreements which limit their use and disclosure of all information they obtain through their relationship with us to Fool-related business only, consistent with this policy.
  * **Legal Requests:** We may disclose your personally identifiable information to protect the rights and property of The Motley Fool as well as to comply with any applicable law.

**Security**

The Motley Fool takes reasonable steps to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.  All information that you provide to us is stored on secure servers.

While we do our best to protect your personal information, The Motley Fool cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. What does all this mean? Just as in the investing world, you must protect yourself. You are responsible for maintaining the secrecy of any passwords and account information you reveal on the internet.

**Access to and Amending Your Information**

Upon written request, The Motley Fool may provide you access to the personal information we hold about you.   Provision of such information may be subject to a reasonable fee.

Please ensure that the personal information that you have actively provided to us is correct, complete and not misleading.  In the event that you would like to make a correction to the personal information that you provided previously (through your oversight or otherwise), we will be able to do to so, subject to a reasonable fee.

**Retaining Your Information**

The Motley Fool may retain your information for as long as we need to provide services to you or as otherwise required by law.

Once it is no longer necessary for us to retain your personal information, we may dispose of this information in a permanent and secure manner.

**Links to Other Websites   **

If you follow or click on links to any third party websites from Fool.sg, you should be aware that these other sites have their own privacy and data processing practices. The Motley Fool has no responsibility or liability for these independent policies.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

The Motley Fool may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time. Any substantive changes will be announced on the site.  Your continued use of the website and related services will signify your acceptance of any new terms.

Last Updated: 25 October 2016
